The soldiers had their lives squeezed
out of them like fruit being juiced...
...and their scraps cast into the sea.
I suppose I should
explain what the sea is.
The sea is a body of salt water that
covers 70% of our world's surface.
"Attack Titan"
Sync and corrections by masaca
- addic7ed.com -
Owl... Who are you?
I am Eren Kruger.
As you just saw, I possess
one of the Nine Titans.
In other words, I'm a Subject
of Ymir, just like you.
You pretended to be a Marleyan
and infiltrated Public Security?
What about the blood tests?!
That was easy enough with
the help of a doctor.
Doctors make good spies.
In all honesty, you did very well.
But in terms of results, Grice had
every right to grieve like he did.
You're absolutely right...
I was a useless father, a useless
husband, and a useless man.
And yet, why am I the only one
who remains as a human?
Dina was someone special, being a
Subject of Ymir with royal blood.
She can tap into a Titan's true power.
If you hadn't jumped to keep
me quiet, Dina would...
Answer me!
Why did you let only me live?!
Enough. Don't your fingers hurt?
Thanks so much for your concern!
You didn't seem to care so much
when you were chopping them off!
Well?! If you had gone on a rampage
as your Titan sooner,
wouldn't the others not
be Titans right now?!
What was the whole point of
letting them become Titans?!
What's wrong? You look pale...
It wasn't just fellow patriots...
I've severed thousands of fingers
from Subjects of Ymir...
...and made them into Titans.
Women and children, too...
All while believing it was
for the sake of Eldia.
I don't have much time, Grisha.
I'm entrusting you with the final task.
Not anyone else. Just you.
That day... The day I first met you,
if none of that had happened,
you wouldn't have festered enough
hatred of Marley to come this far.
Is that... the reason you chose me?
That's part of it.
The country...
Your father... Yourself...
The hate in your eyes was enough
to burn the world to ashes.
I was once like that, too...
The royal family that stayed
behind formed a revolution.
My father was part of it.
However, they accomplished
nothing at all...
...and were burned alive.
I was so young, all I could do was peek
through the closet door and watch.
Ever since then, I've sworn revenge
on Marley and the revival of Eldia.
But all I've managed to do is cut
the fingers off my fellow patriots,
kick them off this wall,
and turn them into Titans.
It's because of the things I've done that
my true identity was never discovered.
I'm no different than when I was little.
Perhaps I'm still looking at the world
through a crack from the closet.
Tell me, Owl.
What is this task left for me?
It's to infiltrate the walls and
retake the Founding Titan.
After you inherit my Titan, that is.
What did you say?
That would mean... you...
I'll be eaten by you as a Titan.
You'll take the Founding Titan
from its owner the same way.
Why aren't you doing it?
Those who inherit the power of
the Nine Titans perish in 13 years.
I inherited this power 13 years ago.
The Owl called it "The Curse of Ymir."
The founder Ymir lived that long
after her powers awakened,
so it's only appropriate
we live that long, too.
I've got 13 years left...
And you...
Eight years left... Not even.
You're wrong.
This has to be... a mistake.
It's wrong.
If one possessing the power of the
Nine Titans dies without passing it on,
the power is inherited by a baby
yet to be born by a Subject of Ymir.
It's as if all the Subjects of Ymir are
connected by something we can't see.
One inheritor said they saw paths.
The blood and bones that form a Titan,
and at times, even memories and
thoughts are sent through those paths.
All the paths cross at
a single coordinate.
In other words, that's...
...the Founding Titan.
Every single Subject of Ymir
is connected to that coordinate.
Who was the founder Ymir exactly?
Under Marley authority,
she's a pawn of the devil.
During the Eldian Empire era,
she was a miracle of God.
Some say she touched the
source of all living matter.
Who's to say they're wrong?
Huh?
The only truth in this world
is that there is no truth.
Anyone can become a god or a devil.
All it takes is for
people to believe it.
You're the one who said that
Dina had royal blood in her.
Was that a "truth" of yours?
Unfortunately, Dina having
royal blood was true.
Then why abandon her?
Precisely because she had royal blood.
I couldn't let the enemy have her.
It had to be done before Zeke
told Marley everything.
Even so...
Even so?
Would she be better off giving birth to
children for the enemy her entire life?
I've done my duty. You do yours.
Only someone with the power of the
Titans is capable of reaching the walls.
To be perfectly honest,
I don't think I'm fit for the job.
You will do it.
Look at that...
He was eaten alive by a Titan.
And you asked if watching
that was interesting?
It wasn't interesting at all.
His screams of agony
were unbearable to hear.
I... didn't know any better.
If I had known this was the price
of freedom, I wouldn't have paid it.
Stand.
Fight!
For the sake of restoring
freedom and dignity to Eldia...
Stand!
I...
...can't.
Look. I brought this from your home.
I can't look.
You can't look.
Can't stand. Can't fight.
Have you no balls?
Did Marley castrate you?
It's pointless to try and
make me recall my hatred.
All I have left now...
...are my sins.
That's more than enough.
The main reason I picked you was
because you left the walls that day.
That day, if you hadn't taken your
little sister and gone past the walls,
you would've taken over
your father's clinic,
your sister may have grown up,
married, and even had children.
But you did go outside the walls.
Ever since the first day I kicked
a patriot off this wall...
Ever since that day you took
your sister outside the walls...
We must push forward until
the price of our actions is paid.
Even in death and after death.
This is...
...a story that you began, is it not?
There are names given
to each of the Nine Titans.
That includes the
Titan you will inherit.
No matter which era this
Titan has found itself in,
it has pushed ever forward,
seeking out freedom.
For the sake of freedom, it fights.
Its name...
The Attack Titan.
What are you doing?
Didn't you just do that?
No.
Huh?! He did that, right?
Didn't you two see it just now?
Yeah, but that was...
See?! What was that all about, Eren?
No, it's nothing.
It's the name of your Titan, isn't it?
What were you doing talking to yourself?
Enough, Hange. He's 15 years old.
Everyone goes through a phase.
Huh? What kind of phase
are we talking about?
Hange, I'll explain to you later.
It's not right with him here.
Huh? What do you mean by that?
What the hell did you come for?!
Get out.
I'm supposed to be disciplined
for ten more days.
It's over.
Hange just now was punishment enough.
We had a talk with Premier Zachary,
so don't worry about it.
If we jail the heroes who toppled
the Armored and Colossal Titan,
it kinda sends a bad message, you know?
Plus, you were defying us morons who let
the Beast and Armored Titan get away.
That's not...
Did you lose some weight?
We had plenty to eat, though.
You seem... good.
I guess...
Let's go. Get dressed quick.
Where are we going?
To an audience.
Her Majesty has come to Trost.
To my dear Historia...
As I'm writing this,
Reiner stands next to me.
It's pretty obvious that he's
sneaking peeks at this love letter.
He can be such a creep.
No wonder he's single.
However, he did promise me
he'd deliver this letter to you.
He says it's payback for
saving them that one time.
I'm sorry about then.
I never imagined I would end up
choosing them over you.
It won't be long till I die.
But I have no regrets.
That's what I'd like to say,
but there is one thing...
It's that I wasn't able to marry you.
Sincerely, Ymir.
All the paths cross at
a single coordinate.
In other words, that's...
...the Founding Titan.
What... was that?
Something wrong?
Uh, no...
Is that all there was?
Yes.
Of course, I doubt she was able
to write anything beneficial for us.
Was there any secret message
only you would know?
Like a code?
I don't know.
But I doubt she would
do something like that.
Ymir's such a dummy...
Such a dummy.
You'd play it off the second
you're embarrassed...
I just never know with you...
We're here.
Come in.
Your Majesty.
...Your Majesty.
S-Stop it.
It's not an official position yet.
So much has happened, hasn't it?
But all I did was stare at the
south sky from within the walls.
It's an important duty of yours
just to stay alive.
Yeah, that's right.
I'm glad to see you're
all acting like usual.
Well, that's...
It just hasn't sunk in for us yet.
Shall we get this going?
The Early Life of Grisha Yeager.
The Extent of Our Knowledge
of Titans and Their History.
Information About the
World Beyond the Walls.
The only people who know about
the existence of these books
are those here in this very room.
These were gained by the
efforts of nine living Scouts...
...and the 199 others
who are not here today.
Today, and in the Queen's presence,
I would like to assess our situation...
...and establish an agreement
in terms of our course of action.
Scout Regiment Commander Hange Zoë.
Sir.
The Scouts have lost a great
deal, including Erwin Smith.
But in exchange for the
many heroes that we lost,
we have retaken Wall Maria and
stolen the Colossal Titan's powers.
However, humanity that lives within the
walls remains in a precarious situation.
It would be a relief were Titans
the only monsters we had for enemies.
...However, the true identity of
the enemies we've been fighting
...Then who's the enemy?!
...Enemy?
...are humans. A civilization.
You could even say...
...If I said that, the...
......the world.
According to these,
we're a special race called Subjects
of Ymir who can turn into Titans.
There's also a belief that we
may rule the world again.
That's why the world wishes to
eradicate us Subjects of Ymir for good.
If the Founding Titan falls into
Marley hands, Eldians are done for.
The King in the walls wouldn't
allow that to happen.
The King in the walls won't fight.
Huh?
"If once again Eldia is driven to sin,
we will perish as it's meant to be.
I have made a vow renouncing war
with the Founding Titan."
He said that to the royal family on the
continent and then closed the walls.
Did he not warn that the Titans of
the walls would flatten the earth?
Those words were meant
to deter an attack.
It allowed for a brief time of peace.
The King of the walls stole
his people's memories
and made them believe humanity
perished beyond the walls.
He surrounded himself with the ignorant
and babbled about paradise.
A King who can't protect
his people is no King.
You must find that cowardly King
and strip him of the Founding Titan.
That is our mission.
Mr. Jaeger later achieved his mission
and entrusted the Founding
Titan to his son Eren.
In order to wield the
Founding Titan's full power,
it must be possessed by
someone with royal blood.
However, even if that person
possesses the Founding Titan,
they're enslaved by the King's ideals,
which only leads them down
the path to humanity's downfall.
That is the vow renouncing war.
However, Eren was able
to control Pure Titans
in the past to escape
a dire situation.
So it may be possible even
without royal blood
for Eren to wield that power as well.
That's right...
Just for that split second,
it felt like everything connected.
Why?
Why just then?
My name is Dina Fritz.
I'm a descendant of the royal family.
It can't be!
You scared me. What was that about?
U-Uh... I-I...
Please continue, our Titan.
It's... nothing.
Huh?
Sorry for interrupting the meeting.
Oh? I see... Right...
It would seem that he is
having a phase of sorts.
One where he acts up
and randomly yells things.
Ah, I see. That's unfortunate.
He's that age, I guess.
Eren?
I haven't told those two about
it, either...
That the Titan who
killed my mom and Hannes
was actually someone my dad
was married to before.
What's more, if I talk about it...
If someone with royal blood
is made into a Titan that I touch,
it might be possible for me to use
the Founding Titan's powers.
That's right...
It's just a possibility...
But if they knew of that possibility,
what would the military do to Historia?
Have a family.
Huh?
After you enter the
walls, build a family.
What are you talking about?
I have Dina...
Won't I forget the things you tell me
just before I become a Titan anyways?
That's not always the case.
And someone may see it later.
Eh?
Your wife, your child,
your neighbors if need be...
Love someone inside the walls.
If you can't do that, it'll only repeat.
The same history... The same
mistakes... Over and over...
To save Mikasa, Armin, and everyone
else, you must see it through.
Mikasa? Armin? Who is that?
Who knows? I'm not sure...
Whose memories are those?
Sync and corrections by masaca
- addic7ed.com -
They believed freedom
would come if they fought.
After viewing the sea
on the outside world,
what runs through their minds now,
knowing the truth of humanity?
Next episode: "The
Other Side of the Wall."
"The Other Side of the Wall"